So in your AMC how much is the funds
through MFDs and how much is through
direct? 90% is from distributors of that
90 because let's be honest what does a
client come to a advisor or a
distributor for they come for creating
some route to a financial goal that will
change their life right because this is
not their day job right this is our day
job we can but the ability to take that
experience and give the comfort to the
investor sir you were into this industry
for the last 30 years yes how did you
see the journey of this mutual mutual
fund penetration because there are
multi-waggers in mutual funds today.
Mutual funds became financial instrument
in the investor's life. 2% of their
investment portfolio of 5% or to
somebody who maybe 100% of their
investments are in mutual funds. I'm
just saying 34% of the population
participating in mutual funds is doing
good. What in case tomorrow the
participation of the population
increases those kind of companies and
shares are available in Indian economy
today? Firstly, I think it's a myth to
believe that the wealth creation journey
for anybody over the next 5 to 10 years,
if tomorrow that number was not 5
crores, it is 10 crores, 15 crores, do
you believe there is enough opportunity
hopefully will become even more relevant
as India becomes the third largest
economy. So when we look at the per
capita income income for the NRS in
terms of INR, they make much decent
money compared to average Indian. So how
do you see the opportunity for them to
invest in Indian mutual funds? NRIs
historically if you think about it have
always had great comfort fixed deposits
whether it is NRE deposits the next 20
years for this country which is really
the Vixit bat objective that has been
set out but any specific things to
attract NRS for future. I think our big
focus is like sir coming to the
youngsters yes who are at to start their
first paycheck what is your
recommendation or suggestion to the
youngsters to start building their
wealth for the future and the
combination of health and term because
you know buying as important now this
may come found strange coming from a
mutual fund person saying how are you
saying that a 20-year-old should buy
health insurance first but of all the
things you spend money on medical costs
have gone through the roof.
[Music]
Hi, welcome welcome to RP. Today I'm at
Mumbai with Mr. Anthony MD and CEO of
Mahindra Mutual Funds. He also
chairperson in Ampy. Today let us talk
to Anthony sir and know more about
mutual funds and financial planning.
Welcome Anthony sir. Thank you Raasan
and thank you for the opportunity my
pleasure sir you giving us opportunity
to talk to you. Sir my first question to
you is sir my most favorite topic so I
wanted to know from you as in head of
AMC so in your AMC how much is the funds
through MFDs and how much is through
direct may I know that so interesting
you asked this question because we are
probably the one fund that has the
highest percentage of AUM contribution
by MFDs 90% is from distributors of that
90 because obviously you have banks you
of uh national distributors. I would say
80% of that is MFDs. MFDs have been very
kind to us. Sir, how do you see the role
of an MFD in the turbulent times like
recent 6 months, 7 months? See, I can
answer it at two levels. One is I don't
see any change in the role because uh at
some level you would argue that an MFD
is the client's best friend through all
periods of time. But at another level I
would argue that at turbulent times uh
there is a higher role for the MFT
because let's be honest what does a
client come to a advisor or a
distributor for? They come for creating
some route to a financial goal that will
change their life. Right? When the going
is good highly likely that the client
will actually not reach out. But when
the going is tough that's when the
self-doubt start to come in because this
is not their day job. Right? This is our
day job. We can talk about history last
30 years. You know, markets have not
always gone up. These are periods of
time. You should stay invested. But the
ability to take that experience and give
the comfort to the investor I would say
is invaluable in these turbulent times.
I can
remember you know these I wouldn't even
say are that turbulent times right the
last 6 months. But if I was to think
about the kind of investor panic that
would have set in in March 2020 when
COVID had just started when most people
said that the world is perhaps coming to
an end. I remember sometimes meeting
some clients who would say what is the
it doesn't matter the whole world is
going to come to an end what difference
does it make if my portfolio drops 50 or
100% I'm not going to be around. I mean
there are the extreme thoughts right and
I can I know many MFDs who made a
massive effort to convince customers not
to invest because that is very
challenging you know when times are
really difficult to say you put money
people should ideally do it but it's
very tough but just the journey of an
MFD calming somebody and saying don't do
anything rash has so much implications
on the wealth that then happens right so
I would put it this way I think an MFD
has a role in kinds of times, right?
Because the MFD is supposed to be the
client's best friend in their wealth
creation journey uh through life. That's
I would say the ideal scenario. That
being said, in difficult times, I think
that's the time the client needs you to
reach out. So, it's not even about are
you going to be able to be available for
the client when they reach out. I think
in turbulent times, there are lots of
opportunities for MFDs to reach out and
I see a lot of them that do it, right? I
mean the biggest example I remember is
perhaps not the last 6 months. I
remember March 2020 so much of panic
people wondering whether the world
itself is coming to an end right and
people wanting to perhaps redeem every
single amount of money and lot of MFDs
made efforts to keep those clients
calmer not do anything rash while if I
was I'm not saying that there are not
investors who invest directly but my
point would be if you are an investor
who for some reason has a deep
understanding of markets long-standing
experience of investing which will make
sure you do the right things then yes
direct can work for you but I think that
is 1 2% of the population if you ask me
for 98% of the population you need
advice I can give you a different
example rather I still believe uh that
even when it comes to my own personal
investing even if I obviously it would
be bizarre if I invested in my own fund
other than direct because it's easy to
do it but I will reach out to MFD
friends and just try to figure out what
are they thinking. They have the
perspective of getting an opportunity to
listen to fund managers from other
fundouses not just me. So it's a role
that is very very underappreciated if
you ask me the role of an MFD in that
wealth creation journey. Too many people
spend time giving media bites about the
saving of
the.5% the8%.
I I'm very clear the journey is about
creating the 12% compounded for 20 years
that is wealth creation. Saving 0.5% for
20 years is not going to get you there.
Great sir. Sir you were into this
industry for the last 30 years. Yes. How
do you see the journey of this mutual
fund penetration? Because there are
multi-waggers in mutual funds today. We
have lot many funds from different AMCs
which have grown thousand times at least
350 times, 400 times from 1995 93 kind
of thing. So how did it changed even
after introducing this direct and
regular will it help industry? It has
helped to some degree but if you ask me
there is so there is a big change
obviously in the 30 years that I've been
part of this industry I would it may be
coincidental or it may be a reason
mutual funds became something of a
acceptable financial instrument in the
investor's life in an investor who for
whom mutual funds are only 2% of their
investment portfolio of 5% or to
somebody who maybe 100% of their
investments are in mutual funds I'm just
saying Both sets of people acknowledge
that mutual funds is a good thing which
is a thing that I've seen happen quite
clearly in the last 7 8 years. Having
said that I would still say and this is
not necessarily an direct answer to is
it different from direct and regular. I
would say however in regular we have the
opportunity
uh of trying to bridge the gap between
investor return and investment return.
Right. So you very rightly said that
there are funds that were set up in the
'90s or in the early 2000s which are up
100 times in terms of NAV or 50 times
etc. It may sound very fantastic real
end of the date is just nothing but 13
14% compounded return. How many
investors were able to last that journey
uh I would say is very low compared to
where it should be. uh and I think
that's a journey the industry still has
to figure out and the distributor
community is I would say equally
responsible now I don't mean it in a
blame standpoint but we can't as a
mutual fund industry solve it right
because you all are the handholders of
the customer right so I can send
emailers I can do webinars I can do
conversations like this uh but only you
can have deep conversations with each
customer and I think that's the next
journey for us How do we bridge that gap
100 times? How many of our customers
actually got the 100 times? So you mean
to say it's not a sale, it is a relation
building with the client for NFT. 100%.
That fear. I think that is that is an
absolute given. Perfect sir. So there
are fears in the market saying that
people those are not into mutual fund
not experienced the equity say that if
today with the 3 4% of the population
participating in mutual funds is doing
good. What in case tomorrow the
participation of the population
increases will there be those kind of
companies and shares are available in
Indian economy today if the un of sudden
the investors from today's whatever
percentage become double triple will the
industry able to manage that assets if
there is inflow doubling tripling in
next 5 years see I can actually answer
this question and I'll take an entire
day to do it uh but let me try and give
you a a shorter answer please uh firstly
I think it's a myth to believe that the
wealth creation journey for anybody is
only to be delivered through equity.
Okay. So I would put that point first.
The opportunity in an Indian context is
that you can do Indian equities. Fixed
income is an opportunity as well and as
we particularly see in the last 2 three
years gold is also an opportunity. True
sir. If I look at it and say over the
next 5 to 10 years today as an industry
we manage money for probably 5 cr unique
panh holders if tomorrow that number was
not 5 crores it is 10 crores 15 crores
do you believe there is enough
opportunity between the various fixed
income equity and gold think again two
ways to look at this over the next 5 to
10 years the kind of sectors subsectors
industries that hopefully will become
come even more relevant as India becomes
the third largest economy in time and so
on so forth. Uh means that there'll be
enough number of companies that will
come to marketplace for you to buy. But
I just want to place another perspective
on this. Okay. Uh and I'll be careful
because I could go on for a day on this
perspective but I'll try to keep this
short which is that I think it's a myth
where people think that the wealth
creation journey has to only happen via
equities. Uh right. I think there's
enough opportunity for example in a
diversified portfolio one of the
products that the industry has created
in the last uh 2 three years which is
multi-asset is a great answer right it
is impossible that in the next 5 to 10
or 15 years you'll have a situation
where every asset class does not perform
trust me we'll have bigger problems than
what is happening with our investments
if that happened right and according to
me the journey of this industry which in
last 30 years let's say has resulted in
5 cr unique investors being part of this
industry. It's very easy frankly for the
industry to be able to manage a number
which is closer to 10 or 15 crores
without even worrying about where is the
extra supply of paper going to come. To
my mind this industry has the ability to
grow at least five or 10 times from here
before something like that becomes an
issue. The last part I will also put in
front of you as our country develops. We
will probably provide opportunities to
invest not just in India already have
many feeder funds etc. Right. So I don't
think that's the worry that can we
manage if this became 10 times what is
coming. I think that's very very easy.
Yes sir. I do agree mutual funds is the
only vehicle wherein we are today
sitting in India. We are participating
in pure real estate through funds. Uh
some countries like China, Brazil
whenever we see an opportunity. Yes sir.
So that's but but the question is for
the people those are not entered into
mutual fund for many people thinking of
mutual fund is just an equity. Yeah well
said sir that's well said. So now my
next question is so when we look at the
per capita income so if we look the same
per capita income for the NRS in terms
of INR they make much decent money
compared to average Indian. Correct. So
how do you see the opportunity for them
to invest in Indian mutual funds?
Because my point is as I spoke to most
of NASA I manage many NRAs today across
globe. So when I look at their net worth
in India their net worth in India the
percentage of allocation towards the
Indian mutual fund is hardly below 5% of
their overall network. How do you see it
as an opportunity both for MFD as well
as an NRS to invest in India? Sir I
think it is a massive opportunity. It's
a bigger opportunity to me than the
opportunity for resident Indians. I will
also equally say that even today we have
scratched the surface right you think
about it in the last 30 years our
capital markets have delivered arguably
12 to 14% return give or take whichever
index the first biggest beneficiary of
it has been the foreign institutional
investor actually they have been the
largest buyers of Indian equity over
these last 30 years domestic investors
have been probably third in the list
only in the last five seven years people
have started to use mutual funds in a
large scale NIS historically if you
think about it have always had great
comfort in giving fixed deposits whether
it is NE deposits or large forms of
remittances right I have an advantage
over and I'm living in the US or
Australia or the Middle East right I
think I have an advantage over any other
citizen of other nationalities I still
understand India right that's where I
came from and I think the journey that
the next 20 years for this country which
is really the vixit bat objective that
has been set out. You go back in
history, you look countries like Korea,
Japan, Taiwan, even the US maybe about a
century ago. People believe and there
are lots of very qualified historians
and economists who say this, the
creation of prosperity that happens when
a country moves from developing to
developed is a unique moment in the
history of that country for centuries.
not for decades, for centuries, right? I
think there is reasonable conviction
that that moment of 20 25 years for
India is now. And so for any NRI that
still has close ties to this country,
this is a is an opportunity. And to the
point that we've had in this
conversation, if I'm sitting in Seattle,
if I'm sitting in Melbourne, if I'm
sitting in Dubai, I know this, I
understand this, but how am I going to
make this happen? Uh, a lot of people
don't know this. uh and I'll just share
this with you because as you know on NFI
I have a couple of other roles as well
on the operations and close to 96% of
the transactions in our industry and
it's typically you know maybe 40 50 lakh
like transactions a day happen paperless
which means that for a customer sitting
in Hyderabad or Chennai Mumbai or
Melbourne or Seattle your ability Ram
Prasad to give the service required is
actually identical. So my belief is that
for the MFDs also this is a large
opportunity. It's not just about how
many customers in the city I work in or
I am operating in are investing. Uh I
think all of you know you think about
people in sales always teach you right
you know references is a very good way
of doing business. I would believe the
question should not be that please tell
me about your friends and neighbors who
are next to you. Please tell me about
your friends and family who are also
outside India. I think it's as big if
not bigger opportunity. True sir. True
sir. So is there any steps from AMP side
to attract the NR investors? We do a
campaign like a common campaign mutual
fund. Yes, that helped us. I'm a police
or all the industry but any specific
things to attract uh NRS not right now
but you bring up an interesting point
actually I'll take this Ram as a
suggestion right that we when we start
identifying client segments for future I
think our big focus is like how do we
change the 5 cr unique investors to 10
cr uh I don't think the messaging needs
to change maybe we don't need to explain
they know what mutual funds are they
used to investing maybe the mediums we
used to advertise, right? I mean, so for
example, arguably I
remember in the last T20 World Cup in
the US, you look at most of the
stadiums, they were all full of
non-resident Indians, right? So
potentially could you use that as a
medium to advertise because then you
have a lot of the local population
there. So I think it's about which
mediums you choose that the NRS
potentially will see, right? I still
have personally family and I'm sure
Ramasad you do as well. they still have
some of their viewing not just in
Netflix there are still some local
channels right if I'm from Andra or
Telangana there will be a Telugu channel
that is there on my pay TV if I'm from
Goa like I am I will still follow some
conani channel if I can so I think it's
a medium but I I'll take this as a
suggestion I I I don't think I could say
oh no no we're doing this or that I
think it's a since we're having this
conversation I think the NRI is a
segment we don't think about as you know
How do we change the perhaps 3 500,000
NR customers who've invested in the last
1 month for the first time? Why can it
not be 5 50 lakh? Okay. The reason for
me to bring this that when I look at the
ticket size of my investors, NAS are
doing on an average a big ticket like
three lakhs per month, four lakhs they
have got that potential to do. But but
few cases now when NRA visits India he
first goes to his hometown he buy a
property after that he comes to me
saying that we just purchased a property
which is worth 3 cr now I am left with
20 20 lakhs 30 lakhs can can we plan
something into mutual fund so that's
where I see there lot of net worth is
built in 95% of the NRS net worth is in
real estate and the biggest challenge in
future is repatating this back to their
country because there is no certainty
that whether they come back or not repat
is one bigger challenge now when they
invest through NRE. I think so. And I
think ownership is also potentially a
challenge as it moves to the next
generation. I I at least personally have
seen some stories where I've actually
seen some non-resident Indians spend
extra effort actually exiting real
estate because they're very clear that
if the next generation isn't coming back
to India, it's not very viable for them
to keep it. Even for them you know for
you and me if we have an extra apartment
we for us to give it on leave and
license is the easiest thing in the
world. Yes. But for them now assuming it
goes to the next generation there are
hiccups. So converting a part or a lot
of that real estate holding into mutual
funds I would say is one of the most
obvious things and I I again stress the
point right it's not about trying to
convert it into equity because that's
what people sometimes think that oh only
that is a right replacement I think
across equity multi-asset funds hybrid
funds any of them could be possible
roots for some of this real estate
divestment because clearly for them I
think investing in real estate going
forward is going to be a much larger
challenge than it has been maybe 10 15
years ago when they did talking about
NAS NAS are not aware that they are not
allowed to buy agriculture land in India
when I bring up this on table they
surprised no no one told us how can you
say NAS are not allowed to buy
agriculture land it's not N OCI is not
allowed to buy agriculture land NS can
buy that's what they're under the
assumption so so that's why I'm saying
that that there it is a large
opportunity because they have
significant amount of wealth health
they're looking to avenues to deploy and
like I told you about my theory on this
developing to developed right many of
them are sitting in developed countries
there is a return trajectory that
happens with developed countries right
you have inflation at 2% interest rates
at four uh equity markets are typically
outside of the US most uh developed
markets tend to range to 8 to 10 right
so that to me there's a big opportunity
and as the digitization of records in
India happen it is going to become more
and more challenging. I think in the
past people found workarounds but you
know you remember this budget there is
this announcement that in fact land
records will be digitized and then a lot
of that if it is the the law of the land
says you can't maybe for 10 years nobody
knew but now that it is digitized
somebody's going to insist on an Aadhaar
they will insist on a PAN lots of people
don't understand the PAN number for an
NRI has a different lettering to
recognize it's NRI right yes sir and
tech is the easiest tech to figure out
so If I was an NRI, India has still
incredible opportunities. But I just
think you need to go beyond the
conventional way of thinking about it
which is conventionally I think it's
been about let me buy a property whether
it's land or an apartment, let me do an
NRE deposit, let me just focus on
remittances. I think moving beyond that
to capital markets for NRIs is a very
very large kind of scope that I don't
think we've tapped at all. Yes sir.
That's what I feel they should know that
they can invest in any asset class
through mutual fund first N when they
owns a commercial property and paying
GST having a TDS. Yeah, even a essential
property when the owner is an NRA he
need to have a TDS cut and all while
making the transaction also people are
making mistakes not disclosing as NR and
all in future that might turn to be a
bigger challenge for them. So we want to
bring it in public that they have
awareness about it and if you permit me
to be a
little sentiment I think it will time
will not be far where some of them may
actually say I may not wish to stay in
this country. I'd probably prefer to be
comfortable back in India. Now just
think about it. I have historically
bought an apartment in Punea for
argument sake. All right. 10 years from
now I've taken a call I'd like to come
back uh and I'd like to come back and
I'd like to live in Bangalore because
I'm a technology guy and there's a lot
of interesting work now I can't go and
live in my apartment in Punea and do
something in Bangalore right so the
point is actually having physical assets
doesn't help but if you've created
enough of a wealth in India as well it
gives you that optionality is my view I
think when you and I have grown
The direction has always been resident
to non-resident. I'll argue this. I
think 10 years from now we will be
talking about a concept what happens
when a non-resident wishes to be a
resident. Yeah. And this country has
enough opportunities for that. Right. So
that also is a reason for probably a
non-resident uh to think about creating
a decent portfolio in India. Great sir.
So I I don't know whether to ask this
question is the right question for you
or not. Is there any possibility in
future India allowing dual citizenship?
I don't know many people in other
countries are having a dual citizenship.
Yes. With my experience with NR out of
the wife and husband one is taking the
citizenship one is still keeping because
to protect their assets in India. Yes.
If we allow them for a dual citizenship
that also makes life very easy. So that
honestly Ram Pradat is above my pay
grade because that is I'm sure there are
other considerations but it that's why
I'm saying it doesn't matter with
financial assets right yes true that's
that if we as a country are very
welcoming of foreign institutional
investors we have been that for 30 years
there are many statements from very
senior policy makers that clearly
believe that foreign capital is needed
for the development of many sectors
subsectors infrastructure You then can
say that capital markets will always be
very welcoming to non-resident Indians.
Yes. So the concept of citizenship will
not occur when it comes to capital
market products like mutual funds or for
that matter even you know I mean I'm not
saying a a non-resident Indian buys term
insurance and health insurance but I
know Ram I think that's something people
don't see enough uh you are a very
unique MFD in that perspective right
that combination of mutual fund plus
health plus term which is why I you know
you when you say that you are supposed
to be your customer's best friend for
life. Yes sir. Uh that combination is
very unique. So I must compliment you on
that. Thanks for sir. Coming to the
youngsters. Yes. Who are to start their
first cut the first paycheck. What is
your recommendation or suggestion to the
youngsters to start building their
wealth for the future using mutual fund
as an opportunity? So I'm very glad and
I don't know whether you're asking this
question because you almost know the
answer to uh this based on my last
question. Okay. Uh it seems to be a
combination of perhaps starting a sip in
an equity product because they can take
the risk. They have a lot of wealth
creation journey ahead of them. uh I
think click of a button which is
entirely possible through MFDs as well
because everything is pretty much
digitized paper this and a combination
of health and term because you know
buying if at all I would drop term if I
had to but health I think is as
important now this may come found
strange coming from a mutual fund person
saying how are you saying that a
20-year-old should buy health insurance
first but I'll tell you I And I am sure
all of us have had some personal
experience in the last 5 or 10 years. Of
all the things you spend money on,
medical costs have gone through the
roof. So just think about it. Let's
think of a live example. I have just
finished my engineering or a technology
course or uh commerce degree or
whatever. I've started my job. I earn
six lakh rupees a year, eight lakh
rupees a year. Let's assume that's the
average salary. That would be the case.
I would spend perhaps 50% of it. Uh
because clearly the youngsters today
have a lot more spending affinity than
perhaps we did. Uh which is fine. I mean
that's that's the way they believe life
is is happy for them and that's really
what's most important. But just think
about it. 5 years of doing the saving of
maybe a lack or two a year and some
ailment comes across that requires you
to be in hospital. you can actually go
back pretty much to 20 by the cost of
that particular thing. Right? So I think
the good old days where people thought
buying a five lakh 10 lakh health
insurance is uh more than enough is long
gone. Yes sir. And even if I was a
youngster, it doesn't cost a lot of
money to buy a 25 lakh health insurance
policy when you're 22 years old. Right.
Because even life insurance or health
insurance companies understand that the
likelihood of you actually using it is
low. So the premiums are lower right
that's how it all works. So I would say
start an SIP in a equity diversified
fund. Don't again do too fancy stuff
sector fund thematic just do a simple
flexi multicap fund and buy health
insurance for yourself. And uh the other
thing I would suggest uh is uh yourself
some time. It's going to sound strange.
Buy yourself some time to learn about
investing. So, because I think for
somebody who even uses an MFD, it's
really important for people to
understand why they're investing where
they're investing. You know, frankly, I
think back I don't know, I'm going to
switch it and ask you after I finish,
right? place of I feel that if I knew
about investing basics not even fancy
stuff basics if I knew when I was 20 22
23 even though I was working in mutual
fund industry even then that was my
first job ends up being my last job
probably I would be potentially a lot
wealthier I surely would have invested a
lot better if I had taken the time to
learn these things now but doesn't help
that at 50 I've learned that Don't panic
when markets fall, right? Invest for a
long period of time. What you invest in
doesn't help. Investing for a long
period of time, even if you didn't buy
the best thing, still creates wealth. So
all of those things, right? I mean, I I
don't know. Do you think when you were
20, 25 years old, you had any
understanding of where to invest? No,
sir. One of my ex company CEO when I was
26, he told me to start an SAP of 500
rupees per month. Yeah, I started it and
made it for 11 months and I stopped it.
Yeah. Because I see negative returns.
Yeah. So that's what I would say that
besides actually investing, they need to
invest time in understanding what
they're doing cuz you know we put these
ads on SIP, right? You standard those
ads make your money work as hard as you
do. Uh boon
say and a sip per day makes an ocean.
Yes. of all of that the one thing that I
think you know when I come across very
successful
investors in the marketplace a lot of
them actually are people who don't have
a job and don't have a business they
just invest true sir that's their 100%
life passion business call it what you
may and you realize that all they have
done is that they have invested time in
understanding they have made mistakes
they have learned from those mistakes
and then they've kind of become
successful Right. So my advice to the
youngsters who watch this conversation
is that besides investing and buying
yourself insurance, invest in learning.
Great sir. But from your words about the
anger generation, I want to add one
point here sir. Yes. It's not only for
anger generation as rightly mentioned
there is a high possibility that most of
the NRAs are some of Nas may come back
to India. I recommend all the NAS to
have an health incident in India from
today. This is what I'm ensuring with
all my NR clients because I see lot of
NR falter while coming back are coming
with the pre-existing diseases with that
condition they are declined by the
insuranceers they are thinking once we
go back we buy insurance pol health
insurance policy which is not possible
at all the times health insurance is
given to you when you are healthy be it
an NRA or an angst yes yeah this is the
point I want to make it sir I I mean
Rabad you probably because you do this
and you understand this a lot more
intimately I honestly don't understand
it outside of just knowing that you
should get yourself health insurance
cover. Uh but you know while the cost of
medical facilities in India has gone up
the quality of medical facilities in
many cases is world class. Right. Yes.
So as an NA you you may still choose to
spend a couple of years here just on a
medical treatment and maybe that health
insurance policy you've picked up
actually helps you do that. Right. So
there are all kinds of possibilities. So
yeah makes a lot of sense. However, it
comes at a cost of $1,000 per year for
the entire family to have a cr one cr
and and most of them especially if
they're in the western world probably
don't they are very used to it. If you
fall ill in the western world and you
actually go to a private doctor, it will
set you back a lot of money, right? So,
uh actually for NIS the value of
insurance is well understood is very
well understood, right? So, this is an
interesting side topic which is then
therefore why don't they look at doing
health insurance cover in India as well
in case in case they have a plans in
future to come back. Yeah. You know, I I
I mean I know what you have been doing.
I'm just very interested in
understanding yes you decided to start
selling mutual funds sir what prompted
you to add health and term because I
have witnessed cases when my client
calls me to break his investment the
reason is one of his family member is
ill at hospital so that made me to
realize the importance of health
insurance first today I will not even
onboarding a client single client
without showing me his health insurance
cover. Oh, be it through me or be it
outside. I'm happy with it. Even the
book I written, I mentioned it. Buy a
health insurance policy from a nearby
agent, not from me. Correct? Buy it
first. Not look at the company. All
companies are good. Don't try to do more
research on choosing a company. Correct?
You buy any of the company with an
adequate cover. That's what I clearly
made in most of the channels. Whenever I
go for an interview, I start my
interview with health insurance. And
another thing that I'm sure your clients
know because they are people who
actually done it but a lot of other
people don't is uh you are perhaps one
of the MFDs with the highest per SIP
number. Yes. So why why do you push
people to do 50,000 one lakh SIPs? Yeah.
I I I mean I I we are also beneficiaries
of some of them but I you know people
when they think about SIPs think 3,000
5,000 but you are someone who pushes
people to do 50,000 one lakh because I
want to spend my quality time with the
client my bandwidth should support me
right so initially I have onboarded all
the kind of SIS be from 1,000 2,000 when
I'm growing because I have a practice at
my office in spite having 10 people
we'll never make an outbound call okay
if at all we calling it's for the
onboarded client not to the new clients.
Now there are many clients lined up to
onboard with me with the kind of
establishment I made through my books
and talks in various channels. If
everyone trying to reach me per day 10
onboarding 10 clients a day will make my
life miserable. My bandwidth will not
allow me. Even today with the client
base around 2,000 around 2,000 client
base I have. So even few days I missing
few of the clients call to answer back.
Though my team is in touch with them, I
have recruited service managers. I
spread my clients across nine of my
employees. Everyone is responsible for
200 250 clients. Okay. They're always in
touch. But few clients want to talk to
me on there some change in their life.
Not exactly on investment. Even one big
call they are taking. So for that I need
to be available for them. Right. So
that's the reason I thought of not
increasing the size of the clients but
increasing the investment size. So you
your your share of their wallet is much
higher and then therefore their need for
you is high and your need for them is
also high because there is a there's a
decent value of the relationship. Yes
sir. Yes sir. And mostly whenever I meet
a client first now after looking into
his entire assets liabilities net worth
my first ask to him is try to have a
decent skin in the game. Yeah I ask them
not for the SAP. I ask them to bring at
least 5% or 10% of their overall net
worth into SAP and give me 3 years time
then you decide what need to be done
later. I'm not assuring you 3 years you
make positive returns maybe a negative
return maybe the capital remains same
but the kind of experience you get the
competence it builds anytime liquidity
is the power now it's anytime liquidity
partial liquidity pledge the same units
and make money in minutes of time today
that confidence now having mutual fund
is having your own time your pocket is
what I tell my clients when it comes to
SAP if someone ask me what is a decent
size of SAP SAP I tell them at least try
to buy one future month every month.
What you do per month expenses? If it is
a lakh, you try to do one lakh SAP. What
does it mean? Technically, you are
buying one future month every month. The
mean you have 100 months in your pocket.
You are confident. The way you go to
your office is differs. The way you talk
to your boss differs. So that what I try
to promote for my So you are a innocent
you are the person who is promoting this
whole fire policy. Is it retirement
early? Yes sir. Yes sir. You are the
person who is pushing. So if I become
your customer that is what you are going
to make sure I do retire today. I will
make you retire today. Very good. Very
good. My biggest assment I say I'm
making many people retired where many
people people are not realizing that the
kind of net worth they have today is
more than enough. Their net worth can
only outlive them. They will never be
able to outlive their time. So I want to
enjoy their life. It's not that you quit
your job. You do your job out of choice
not out of compulsion. And I have one
final question Prasad because you have
clearly intersected with both residents
and non-residents across health term
mutual funds and I know that you have a
very large insight in real estate
because you know that a lot of your
clients typically have had that. Are you
planning to add estate planning to your
range of services? Because I'm sure that
is something that people are starting to
wonder about, right? They need help.
We're in plans sir not into that
actually I'm trying to will writing
estate planning I had to do a few
courses and hire people to do that
actually will writing is one service I
realized it recently the all the things
we learn from customers and their
experience and common experiences we are
upgrading ourself here on year soon no
but we need more like you no that
definitely is a there's no point saying
that we want to grow from 5 cr investors
to 10 cr investors we will need RP
wealth to expand otherwise is it's not
going to happen. Sure sir. With your
blessing we do that sir. We'll expand.
It is mutual. You have constantly been a
great support to us at Mahendra and we
really value folks like you because of
the way you do that business. Thank you
very much for giving this wonderful
opportunity sir. Thank you. Thank you.
Right sir. We'll wish to see you again
in our channel. Absolutely. Absolutely.
Right sir. Thank you. Take care. Wish
you all the best. Thanks sir. Thank you.
Thank you.
[Music]